## Tamika Wilson-Byrd

## Research Technician at Monell Chemical Senses Center

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Tamika-Wilson-Byrd/b19cae097b98aa66

A Commerce Engineer with a focus on Chemical Engineering and Operations Management who is keen in finding a management position in the areas of technical operations, and/or planning in a managerial position in a lab, academia, or business setting. Reliable, trustworthy, flexible, able to manage complex projects independently, detailed oriented, experienced with handling confidential information, organized, strong operations and analytic skills, expert in multi-tasking. Able to work on own initiative or as part of a team.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Research Technician

Monell Chemical Senses Center - 2004 to Present

- Coordinated research studies (multiple studies simultaneously)
- · Formulate all chemicals required
- Created SOPs for projects and laboratory procedures
- Developed plans/timelines for projects
- Performed statistical analyses when needed
- · Obtained, organized, and analyzed data
- Supervised summer students/interns
- Ensured all forms and policies were in line with IRB
- Updated websites as needed
- Remained conscious of budgets and worked accordingly
- Coordinate and scheduled doctors, subjects, specialists, etc. as needed

#### **Program Developer/Liaison/Administrative Assistant**

Drexel University - 2002 to Present

- · Mentored, counseled and tutored mainly in S.T.E.M. areas
- Obtained and coordinated speakers for events
- Managed and delivered seminars, panels, and workshops for college-bound students
- Established lasting relationship between enrichment programs, students, and parents
- Developed, scheduled, implemented, and managed student activities on leisure days for required student programs
- · Managed multiple programs simultaneously
- Served as liaison between students and faculty
- · Assisted in fundraising
- Maintained accurate files for students and programs
- Remained aware of budget at all times and worked accordingly

 Managed and presented seminars on personal development (e.g. studying skills, leadership, defining success, and achieving goals)

### Sanitary Engineer Co-op/Intern

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA - 2005 to 2005

- Prepared and oversaw Groundwater permits
- · Reviewed all analytical data obtained from companies to ensure compatibility with laws and standards
- Prepared and calculated sewer rental factors and maintained all spreadsheets and data pertaining
- Assisted in departmental inspections of companies producing wastewater and groundwater
- Organized, distributed, and presented at meetings all information pertaining to groundwater producing companies and there current status
- Organized all analytical and permit information concerning all wastewater producing companies
- Prepared all memorandum concerning permit changes and all occurrences during the inspections so as to update the

entire department

Prepared and analyzed all data for biweekly incident reports

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Science in Business and Engineering**

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA January 2009

## **Associate of Science in Engineering Science**

Community College of Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA 2004

#### Associate of Science in Science (Laboratory Elective)

Community College of Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA January 2004

## Associate in Arts Culture, Science & Technology

Community College of Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA January 2004

#### **Associate of Science in Mathematics**

Community College of Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA January 2004

## **AWARDS**

# Student Leader of the Year 2008 - Drexel University Minority Achievement Program April 2008

#### AMP Awards for best presentation in the category of Engineering:

- Engineering Science Category 2006
- Engineering Science Category 2005

- Physical Science Category 2004
- Mechanical Engineering Category 2002

## **William Norbeck Scholarship Recipient from Drexel University** 2007

"Outstanding Alumnus Recognition Award" from the Community College of Philadelphia's Chapter of the National Society of Black Engineers 2006

"Outstanding Executive Board Member" from the Drexel University Chapter of the National Society of Black Engineers

2006

"Who's Who for Junior Colleges"

2003

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

"Viscosity and density values from excitation level response of piezoelectric-excited cantilever sensors"

http://www.mendeley.com/research/viscosity-and-density-values-from-excitation-level-response-of-piezoelectricexcited-cantilever-sensors/

Sensors and Actuators A. Volume 138(2007) Issue 1 pgs. 45-51

"Chemosensory Loss: Functional Consequences of the World Trade Center Disaster" <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20478761">http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20478761</a>

Environmental Health Perspectives Volume 2010 Sep;118(9):1251-6. Epub 2010 May 13

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

PERSONAL INFORMATION: Date of birth: March 16, 1978 Marital Status: Married Driving License: Clean

#### INTERESTS:

Interests include classical music, studying classical violin, writing sheet music, and studying piano, singing, painting, word games, and puzzles